残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっとくれるもの 求めることに夢中で 運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の定世 窓辺からやがて到達
ほっ飛ばしる熱いパックスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
死人の一生
アトロト
There was no other choice!
Because he was an angel!
Koro was an angel!
He was still an angel!
He was still one of the enemy!
He wasn't! He wasn't!
He wasn't!
Even though he was as human as me?
No! He was an angel!
Is that why you killed him?
Yes! Otherwise we'd all die!
We'd have all been destroyed!
So that's why you killed him?
I didn't want to kill him!
I didn't have a choice!
Help me!
Please, just help me!
For God's sake, help me!
I didn't want to kill him!
Is anyone listening?
Somebody please help me!
He was much better than I am.
Koro should have survived, not me.
No!
The one who deserves to survive is the one who has the will to make it happen!
He wished for death!
He ignored his will to survive and chose to die for a false hope!
Survival is not a mistake, Shinji!
Are you sure?
Are you sure it was right?
I don't understand!
What can I do?
What am I supposed to do?
What was that?
I fear myself?
I fear being hated?
But by whom?
Who is it?
It's my...
Father.
My father abandoned me!
He hates me!
If others hate me, what will I do?
What will I do?
Where am I?
Where am I supposed to go?
I can't see anything.
I don't understand what I feel.
Misato?
Misato!
Hey!
Where are you, Misato?
I can't see!
Hey, where am I supposed to go?
Misato!
Asuka!
Ainami!
Toji!
Kitsuke!
Ritsuko!
Kaji!
Father!
Mother!
Somebody please tell me what I have to do now!
Evangelion Unit 1!
I still have to pilot it?
Even after it made me kill him?
My father and the others tell me that I have to pilot it no matter what I want!
Why do I have to keep fighting after all that's happened?
Mother!
Say something!
Answer me!
Because everyone tells me to.
What do you mean?
It's for the sake of mankind.
Isn't that good enough?
That's right!
Is there something wrong with that?
I'm doing the right thing!
And when I do it, the others appreciate me!
The others like me then!
You're lying!
Huh?
Are you stupid?
You know damn well that you do this for yourself.
Huh?
You're just making up excuses like you always do.
I do?
Pretending you're sacrificing yourself is just another cop-out.
It makes you feel so special to play the martyr.
I'm not sure that's true.
You're feeling lonely and isolated, nothing more.
Am I?
Of course you are!
You live on sympathy and you get it with your Eva, Shinji!
It could be true.
You love having others depend upon you.
It satisfies your twisted little mind.
It could be.
If you want real happiness, you've got to find it for yourself, not wait for someone to give it to you.
But isn't that what you've been doing?
Didn't want to be in this thing again.
They're forcing me to buy like this.
But this piece of junk won't work.
But it's only junk because of what I've become.
I'm the garbage now.
I'm worthless.
Nobody needs me.
But he needs a pilot who can't even control her own Eva!
You seek your own value in the perception of others.
Shut up!
Do you fear being alone?
Do you fear being you afraid that you will lose your identity if others leave you?
You pilot Eva so you'll be preyed!
Shut up!
Leave me alone!
How can a wind-up doll like you dare tell me that?
Who am I?
You are Rei Ayanami.
But who are you?
Are you Rei Ayanami as well?
Correct.
I'm the thing that is recognized as Rei Ayanami.
We are all things that are recognized as Rei Ayanami.
How could all of those possibly be me?
It is simply because the others call us Rei Ayanami.
That is the only reason.
You possess a false body and a fake soul.
Do you know I?
I am neither false nor fake.
I am simply me.
No.
You are an empty shell with a false soul created by a man named Gendo Ikari.
You are just an object that is pretending to be a human.
Look deep within yourself.
Do you perceive the almost intangible and invisible presence that lurks below your waking self?
Inside your darkest dreams, my lord.
It is there that your true identity lies.
No, I am me.
I became myself by the instrumentality of the links and relationships between myself and others.
I am formed by interaction with others.
They create me as I create them.
These relationships and interactions serve to shape the patterns of my heart and mind.
Yes, that is the name for what I share with those who have created the thing known as Rei.
That is what will continue to shape me.
But there is someone else who is your true self.
You don't know her, but she exists.
You deny that fact and attempt to suppress that facet of your reality.
Because she might not have human form.
Because then the present self might cease to be.
This is what you fear, that you will become nothing.
You are frightened that you will disappear from the minds of others if another exists.
I'm afraid.
Why is that?
Because your current self will have never existed.
Because you will cease to be.
No, I'm not.
I am happy.
Because I want to die.
I want despair.
I want to return to nothing.
But I can't.
He won't let me return to nothingness.
Not yet.
I still exist because he needs me.
But when everything is over, when I am of no use anymore, he will abandon me.
I've prayed for the day he would abandon me.
But now, now I fear it.
Come, let us go.
This is the day for which you were created, Rey.
Yes, sir.
What?
What feeling is this?
I think I've experienced this sensation before.
It's as though my physical form was disappearing.
It feels agreeable.
As though my existence is spreading itself out to cover the entirety of existence.
Incorrect.
It is not a return to nothingness.
It is merely a return to a state of beginning.
It is no less than a return to the primal womb that we lost so long ago.
Souls and minds will become one, attaining eternal balance.
The final goal is nothing more than that.
And that's instrumentality.
Yes.
There is an emptiness at the very core of our souls.
A fundamental incompleteness that has haunted all beings since the very first thought.
On a primal level, man has always been aware of the darkness that resides at the core of his mind.
We have seeked to escape from this void and the fear it causes.
And all man's accomplishments were made in the hope of filling it.
And so you'll just crush everyone's minds together to fill the gaps?
Who made you humanity's overseer?
You came to us bearing an offer of help, yet your benevolence has proved to be as false as our friendship.
And yet that is exactly as you wished it to be.
Where am I?
This is the me that exists in your mind, Misato.
And yet at the same time, this is also the me which exists in your mind.
Isn't it, Shinji?
In order to establish my identity, I have to communicate with the minds of many people.
I have to examine that which is at my core.
I have to stare at Misato, who resides on the inside of my mind.
What is it that you wish for, Misato?
I have to be a good child.
Because I have no daddy.
Because I have to be good and not bother my mommy.
But I don't want to become like my mom.
When my father is not here, she always cries.
I can't cry.
I can't depend on anyone else.
So I have to be good.
That way maybe my father won't hate me as much.
I hope.
Maybe my father won't hate me if I be good.
But I hated my father.
And I hated being a good child.
I hate it.
I'm tired of it.
I'm tired of keeping myself clean.
I'm tired of pretending to be pure and noble.
I'm so tired of it all.
I want to disgrace myself to get so dirty that no one can stand it.
I want to see my life and my reputation ruined.
Is that why you slept with him?
With Kaji?
No, I slept with him because I love him.
You did?
Did you really love him?
Yes, I did.
He accepted me as myself for the real me.
That's why I let him make love to me.
No!
Don't show Cindy this.
I don't want him to see that side of me.
Why are you still embarrassed after all that's happened?
Because I'm ashamed of it.
Why does this embarrass you?
You weren't ashamed then.
You were glad to show your true nature to the man you loved.
In fact, you took great pleasure in it.
No, don't do this!
You wanted to dirty yourself.
You should be happy to show this side of yourself to Shinji, shouldn't you?
No!
No, no!
Are you sure?
Or is it perhaps your father that you'd like to show this to?
No!
Wasn't it really peace of mind that you were seeking in Kaji's bed?
You wanted peace of mind and warmth from Kaji then?
No!
You wanted to find your father in Kaji's embrace, didn't you?
Is that true?
It is true.
In Kaji, I had found my father reborn.
And so I fled from him.
I was so afraid.
He was so much like my father.
But at the same time, I was also very happy.
I was never happier.
That was such a wonderful time.
That's why I hated it.
That's why I left.
That's why I ran away.
So, no reason was required to begin our love, but you needed a reason for ending it.
Yes, you were so kind, Kaji.
You were so kind to disgrace me.
To dirty me.
To deflower me.
Just because you hate yourself is no reason to injure yourself further.
Punishing yourself is simply a cheat to make you feel better for a little while.
Don't do this to yourself.
And now you'll tell me to take care of myself?
Men always do that.
They'll escape to their jobs, their own world, and leave me behind.
They always leave me behind.
Always.
Just like our father did.
They always escape from the harsh realities.
Harsh reality.
I am his harsh reality.
Of course, I am the problem.
Stop this!
Misato.
Why should anyone else love me anyway?
I hate myself!
You're vulgar and impure.
You're pathetic.
You're gross and disgusting!
I've never seen anyone in such a disgusting relationship!
Congratulations on your promotion, Major Katsuragi.
The me who's recognized is the me who's performing a role in order to be appreciated.
But she's not the real me.
Your true self is always crying, isn't she?
Yes.
But I am happy.
I am happy.
It's true.
I'm not.
This isn't the happiness I want.
This isn't me.
It is not the true myself.
I just don't want to face the harsh reality.
But we have to.
We cannot live otherwise.
You know you'd be alone and afraid.
Unstable.
If nobody was sleeping next to you.
Are you afraid of sleeping alone?
Or does sleeping by yourself remind you of how empty your life is?
She can't stand not having other souls around her.
So you'll sleep with anyone, won't you, Major?
No!
Yes, you just want to be infatuated with primal ecstasy.
You want to fill the hole in your heart with temporary escape.
You take advantage of men to soothe the pain in your soul.
No!
Where am I?
This is the me which exists in your mind, Asuka.
And also, this is the me that exists in Shinji's mind at the same time.
I can't stop now.
What do you want, Asuka?
I want to live by myself.
I don't want my papa and my mama.
I'll live by myself.
And then, I won't cry anymore.
But I'm still crying.
Why am I crying?
I am sorry.
I just don't like her.
What happened to you, the able doctor?
I told you, I'm a human being before I was old.
But how can a trained person like you?
She acts too much like an adult.
And she rejects me, absolutely.
Sometimes, she even scares me.
Have you had such a feeling with her?
No.
And in any case, you have now become Asuka's mother.
I'm your wife before that.
Both duties are concurrent.
In a social perspective, yes.
But you can't quit being her father.
However, I can quit being her mother anytime.
You can say that.
No, mama!
Don't leave me!
I'll be good!
Promise!
Don't stop being my mother!
Don't ignore me!
No, mama!
Don't kill me!
Your papa hates your mama.
He doesn't need me anymore.
No.
He didn't love me to begin with.
But let's die together.
Because he doesn't want us.
He didn't need me at all.
And he doesn't want you either, Asuka.
I'm not wanted!
I'm not worth anything!
Die with me, too.
No!
I am not your soul!
I'll think by myself and live by myself!
And then, my mother was hanging from the ceiling.
She looked so happy.
But I hated how she looked.
I don't want to die.
I don't want to disappear.
I hate this.
I hate boys.
I hate my father and my mother.
I hate everyone.
Nobody cares about me.
Nobody stays with me.
So I don't want to depend on anybody.
But I hate it at the same time.
It's a pain.
I don't want to be alone.
I don't want to be alone!
Don't leave me.
Don't ignore me.
Don't kill me!
What the hell is this?
This is the instrumentality which your father has initiated.
This is it?
This is part of it.
You can't tell what the truth is, Shinji.
Truth is subjective.
Therefore, you can barely tell that what you can feel is fact.
The truth is within you.
And the facts that remain in your memory are what will become your truth.
Truth can be changed from time to time.
Sometimes.
This is all fact.
This is the result of everything?
This is real, but one of many realities.
This is the conclusion you wanted.
Wanted?
Me?
Yes.
Total destruction.
You wished for a world in which nobody would be saved.
No!
I didn't wish for this!
The others didn't save me!
Nobody can save you from yourself.
This is what you wished for.
Destruction, death, and return to nothingness.
You wished for these.
This is the reality that is.
What is reality?
This is your world.
A world that exists solely for yourself.
One without time, space, or anyone else.
A world in which every facet is determined by you.
This is the world in which you just wait for others to give you something.
This is your world unless you decide to change reality.
This is the world that is!
Nothing can change that!
No.
You yourself make the decision.
This is the world where your mind decides what will be.
Whether it is the will to survive, or a wish for death, it is all up to you.
Are you saying that this darkness, this insane world, are what I really wish to create?
Yes.
You wished for a closed world that was comfortable for you.
You wished for it in order to protect you from your wounds.
To protect your few pleasures.
This is merely the result of your wish.
In your closed world, in a world where only you are allowed to be, others cannot live with you.
But still you wished to close off the world that surrounded you.
Your wish ejected things you disliked, and created an isolated and lonely world filled with nothing.
This is the world your wishes have created.
A private haven in the recesses of your mind.
This is how it all ends.
One of many possible endings.
This is an ending you brought upon yourself.
You choose this fate.
to kiss me.
And feel my heart with love.
But let me sing forever more.
You are all my love.
The path is always acceptable.
In other ways.
Please be true.
I love you, in other words, I love you.